[theme music playing]
[Emilia] Natalie, tell me.
Is he being considered
by the party to run for Senate?
Yes, he is. I thought you already knew.
I'm a man of my words, Miss Aguas.
I hope you are, too.
[Natalie] You just won't stop
flirting with my boyfriend, will you?
Choose. Ivy, or my daddy's support
for your senatorial ambitions?
Why are you so selfish?!
Have you forgotten that we're a family?
We should help each other
instead of going against one another!
Lily, where are you?!
-I miss you so much!
-If I were Lily,
I would probably say,
"Diego, you have to move on
because we lead different lives now."
-[gunshot]
-[Lily screams]
Sorry, did I interrupt you?
I saw an animal, but I missed it.
[Emilia] Arnaldo doesn't know
that Papa already gave that to me,
so I had it transferred under my name.
[Ivy] I'm still buying
your overpriced property.
But let me just remind you, Emilia,
I don't like any of my friends
using me for my money.
Your happy days are over, Tonio.
It's time for you to talk.
I'm already fed up with you.
-Let him eat.
-[grunts]
He won't get far. I'll take care of him.
[Belen] Raul, you need to get back here.
She's coming back to her senses.
Where are you going?
I'm going to take care
of our gambling business.
The senator already gave me the go signal.
I don't care if the devil
himself gave you the go.
If I tell you to stay,
you're going to stay.
If I want to leave this house,
then I will!
Raul!
[suspenseful music playing]
[Belen] She's coming back to her senses.
[exhales]
[car engine rumbling]
[scoffs]
Damn you, Emilia.
[Emilia] I've read the draft
of the publicity materials.
I like it. Have it published already.
All right.
I can't believe it. Is there
really no hope for you two?
I'm really disappointed.
But, Auntie, you did a great job
watching over him!
As you can see, I gave you a bonus.
Oh! I saw the two designer bags
in my room.
You're very generous, Emilia.
Well, Auntie, it's because I'm
a hundred-fifty-million richer.
-That's thanks to Miss Aguas.
-[Claire chuckles]
She's so gullible. [laughs]
Now you got me curious.
I want to meet this woman.
Soon, you will, Auntie.
But not just yet because I'll be busy,
and I need you to run the house.
Starting tomorrow,
my senatorial dreams
will slowly be coming true.
[giggles]
[pants]
[grunts]
[suspenseful music playing]
[panting]
[map alert pings]
[mockingly] Tonio…
You sure you wanna play hide and seek?
[map alert pings]
[tense music swells]
Get up!
Did you think you could get away from me?
How did you find me here?
Sit down!
Boss, please don't kill me!
I have a family!
I won't kill you
if you give me what I want.
You just have to tell me
all of the illegal activities
that Gov. Emilia Ardiente's involved in.
Damn it! Tie him up! He's not talking.
[grunting]
[suspenseful music playing]
He's not leaving this house
no matter what.
You will give him the clothes
he'll wear every day.
And don't forget to put this on him.
Put it somewhere where he won't notice.
-Copy?
-Yes, boss.
Hands behind your head.
We're in the same profession.
Don't do anything stupid now.
Now hands behind your head!
Turn around.
Just so you know, Tonio,
you're not getting away from me.
You will testify against Emilia Ardiente.
Whether you like it or not.
[Carlotta] That Emilia is a parasite!
Nanny, don't worry.
Because the money I gave
will be the end of her.
[phone rings]
-What do you want from me?
-Shut up…
-What do you want from me?!
-I said shut up!
-Jepoy.
-Ivy.
I'll get him to talk. I promise.
[dramatic music playing]
I'm doing you a huge favor,
but you're just wasting it.
-You're not doing me any favors!
-Shut up!
How long have you been working
for the Ardientes?
I quit a long time ago.
I changed because of my children!
[grunts]
Don't drag your kids into this!
Now, tell me.
What did you do to Camia Cruz?
Is Emilia's hit man going to confess now?
I promise, Nanny.
I'll make sure Emilia goes to prison.
Just be strong, Ivy.
I'll leave you to rest, all right?
That's it!
If you don't talk now,
I'm going to bring your kids here
and I'll send you all
to the Pearly Gates together!
Well?!
I'll tell you everything.
I started working as Emilia's hitman…
when she was still mayor.
I have a list of the people
she ordered me to kill.
[suspenseful music swells]
[instrumental theme music playing]
[Lily] They are the owners of that land.
I just gave them back what's truly theirs.
Ivy, thank you.
Thank you so much.
It hurts, Diego, but I have
to stay away from you.
Especially now that my plans
are slowly unfolding.
[instrumental theme music playing]
[tense music playing]
Raul, where are you?
Are you here yet?
[Raul] I don't think
I can make it there, Auntie.
Something came up.
Just keep an eye on her.
And don't let anyone in.
Wait, why? What happened?
[tense music swelling]
[phone vibrating]
[soft, tense music playing]
I started working as Emilia's hit man
when… when she was still mayor.
I have a list of the people
she ordered me to kill.
[Jepoy] Are you the one
who killed Camia Cruz?
Answer me!
Yes, I killed her!
The governor ordered me
to rape and kill Camia Cruz!
[tense music playing]
[phone rings]
-Ivy?
-Jepoy.
-Jepoy, I'm heading there.
-No, don't. We can't risk it.
Listen to me, just this once.
Let me handle this.
[dramatic music playing]
Hi, Madam.
I've deposited Miss Aguas' check
to your account.
Good. What about the other check
I asked you to prepare?
Here it is.
[gushing] Brilliant, Lara!
Okay, you may go now. Leave that here.
Hi, Arnaldo. Good morning.
What do you want for breakfast?
I'll have them cook it.
How about coffee? Did you sleep well?
I'm fine, Mom.
What's this for?
Oh, that's the check I'm going
to donate to the party.
150,000,000 pesos?
Where did you get that much money?
I sold the farmers' land to Ivy.
Coffee?
[Emilia] Ladies and gentlemen, senators…
thank you so much
for accepting my invitation.
I'm sure that you've heard or read
of the press releases I've issued.
[Pablo] Good job, Emilia.
I'm sure your approval rating
will skyrocket.
[giggles shyly]
Well, how about my rating in the party?
[laughter]
Well, with that, I'd like to give you
my generous donation to the party.
Lara!
[exhales in annoyance]
For the party.
[applause]
-Congratulations, Emilia.
-Thank you, Senator.
Or shall I say, future Senator Ardiente?
Oh, thank you so much. [giggles]
-Congratulations.
-Thank you, Senator.
[Emilia] Thank you.
[dramatic music playing]
[tense music playing]
-Bye-bye.
-Thank you, sir. Thank you.
Mom, I'll just take Natalie
and the senator home.
-All right. Bye, Natalie.
-We'll go ahead.
Thank you for coming.
-Emilia, I have to go now.
-Bye, Ivy? Oh, wait.
Thank you so much for your help.
My senatorial dreams
are slowly coming true.
After that, it's the presidency.
How exciting, right?
[exhales] Emilia, don't get too excited.
Don't be so sure of yourself.
You haven't won yet.
And the party hasn't released an
official list of candidates yet.
There's still so much that can happen.
[tense music playing
I have to go.
Jepoy.
Have you taken care of everything?
Here's the video of Tonio's admission
to all of Emilia's crimes.
Say goodbye to your dreams, Emilia.
[Claire] For the success
of Senator Emilia.
-Cheers.
Hey, Raul, I don't wanna see you
with that long face tomorrow.
That's right, Raul. You should
at least be happy for Emilia.
Well, of course.
I'm happy for Emilia. Very.
Actually…
I've been waiting to give this.
Here's my gift for you.
Your favorite beauty products.
All for you.
Are you mocking me?
[scoffs] No. I mean, think about this.
You're in politics, right?
And all politicians age faster.
It's inevitable.
You're going to have a lot of
wrinkles. That's just how it is.
And I don't want that to happen to you.
I mean, your constituents
call you Mommy Emilia right now,
but sooner or later,
they'll call you Grandma Emilia.
[Raul] That doesn't sound good, right?
-Take your gift!
-Hold it!
Can't you take a joke?
These are expensive. Loosen up, Emilia.
Go ahead, Raul. Mock me. Make fun of me.
Treat me like trash.
But if I win the senate race,
you'll regret all of this.
You should be more careful, my love.
Brace yourself for the worst,
because the higher your dreams are…
the harder you'll fall.
[tense music playing]
[Pablo] I know the party seems convinced
that Emilia is going to replace
your grandfather.
But I assure you, Arnaldo,
you are going to get that spot.
Tomorrow's the announcement, Senator.
-What are you going to do?
-[scoffs]
Just trust me.
The question is…
Are you ready to go against
your own mother?
Because I'm telling you, Arnaldo…
she's not going down without a fight.
As a child, this has always been my dream.
And I worked hard, worked as
hard as I can for this.
It's difficult to be a woman in politics.
To be a wife, a mother.
But here I am. I made it.
I am Emilia Ardiente.
I'm destined to be a queen,
and my reign starts today.
[clapping continues]
[laughs lightly]
Thank you for this, Jepoy.
Thank you for everything you've done.
Don't mention it.
So, how are you doing?
I'm fine.
Did anyone bother you while I was away?
Did Diego try to make a move on you again?
I told you, Jepoy.
Diego apologized to me already.
[ice clinking]
He even toured me around town.
The other day…
we went to the places
where we used to play.
Thirteen years.
Jepoy, it's been 13 years.
But he still tells everyone
that I'm his best friend.
I want all this to end.
So I can go back to living a normal life…
and be friends with Diego again.
Friends? Or lovers?
What kind of question is that?
You better report back to Arnaldo.
I'm sure he's looking for you.
Let's talk again tomorrow.
Again, thanks for this.
Hey. Are you ready for tomorrow?
[tense music playing]
Madrigal.
-Reporting for duty, Mayor.
-Good.
Where are we going today?
To Senator Pablo's.
-[door opens]
-Daddy.
-Hi, Natalie.
-[singsong voice] Good morning.
-Good morning, darling.
I dropped by to give you this.
It came in the mail earlier for you.
-Who's it from?
-I don't know. It doesn't say.
Oh, Daddy, I have to go because
I have to check the event venue
for Auntie Emilia's things.
-All right, darling.
-I'll see you.
-Bye.
-[smooches]
Bye, Daddy.
[ominous music playing]
[ominous music swells]
[Emilia humming]
[humming]
Raul, look! It suits me, right?
It sounds really nice.
"Emilia is my senator!"
Come on, Raul.
Can you at least pretend to be
happy when you're with me?
Look at me. I'm happy when I'm with you.
See that?
With you, it feels like I'm spending time…
with my pet dog.
-Hey!
-What did you say?!
[screams] Stop it! Hey!
-[screams]
-Well?
I've just about had it with you, Emilia.
[grunts] Go ahead! Do it!
I dare you!
I know you want me to fail,
but that won't happen.
For as long as I'm in power,
you will stay by my side.
What?!
[exhales]
[cap clattering]
Senator, is everything okay?
Ah, yes. Yes, of course.
Good thing you're here.
I'm very excited to tell you
that you got the vote.
You will be running as senator.
Uh… speaking of that.
Uh…
I'm backing out, Senator.
What?
You cannot do that.
You will run for senator.
That's the deal.
I pulled a lot of strings
for that endorsement.
And now you're going
to chicken out like this?
-I understand.
-No!
No.
Now listen to me, Arnaldo.
You can't back out.
Because if you do that,
I will personally make sure…
that this is going to be the end
of your political career.
Is that clear?
Go.
Get ready for the party.
Do this for Natalie.
For your future.
[tense music swells]
Emilia's greed brought Julio down.
Now, Arnaldo's greed
will do the same to Emilia.
They're like dominoes.
Push one down, you push them all down.
I hope you're enjoying the party.
-Senator.
-Oh. Excuse me.
-Governor Emilia.
-Hi.
-How are you?
-Good, good.
-Raul.
-Senator. Yeah.
Oh, the senators would like
to have a word with you.
-All right. Hello, senators.
-Emilia.
-Senator Magno and Senator Jose.
-Of course, of course.
Oh, Arnaldo. Excuse me.
Arnaldo, where have you been all day?
I've been looking for you at home.
We were already wondering
if you were going to show up.
I know. I'm-- I'm sorry.
I just needed to take care of
something, Mom.
[Natalie] He's so sweet, Auntie.
He actually helped me organize
this whole event.
Oh. Thank you, Natalie.
Oh, by the way. Where's Ivy?
-There she is.
-[Ivy] Gov, I'm sorry I'm late.
Ivy, it's Senator, not Gov.
Sorry, Senator.
By the way, you look so great.
[giggles] Thank you.
Shall we get this party started?
-Sure.
-Let's go.
Okay, I'm sorry. I'll just get a drink.
Sorry, I stepped on your long…
tacky metallic gown.
What? Are you gonna sweep the floor?
You're so thoughtful.
You're so pretty, Natalie.
But you shouldn't have worn your curtains.
That's your comeback? Is that it?
[Magno] I agree with Miss Aguas.
There should be a minimum
educational requirement
for those who wish
to hold government positions.
-[Jose] I'm a lawyer.
-[Pablo] Me, too.
Um, Emilia, we're friends,
but I still don't know
where you graduated from.
Care to tell us?
Um… abroad.
Really? Where? From what university?
Um… Wharton Business School, MBA.
-[Ivy] Top university.
-Mm-hm.
Only a few select people
get to enroll there.
Emilia is so humble
to not list that
in her list of qualifications.
[Pablo] What year did you
graduate there, Emilia?
I know a professor there.
You might know him, too.
Come on, Senator. If I tell you
which year I graduated,
it's like I'm telling you my real age,
and I don't want that. [giggles]
Anyways, could you please excuse me?
I just need to get ready
for my announcement.
Excuse me.
Wharton Business School?
I highly doubt it.
[Magno] So, the rumors are true, then.
Emilia didn't actually
graduate from college?
Obviously, yes. That's why
we made the right call.
[Ivy] Excuse me. Senator Pablo.
So, what's your decision?
You'll see, Miss Aguas.
[tense music playing]
[Emilia sobbing]
[sobbing]
I'll prove to you, bastards,
that I'm better than all of you.
Mr. Mayor? Thank you.
When it comes to service,
you are truly the best.
I need your advice.
Can you hold this, please?
How can I help you?
It's about Mom.
The party won't be choosing her tonight.
What?
But isn't that what you wanted?
Grandpa wanted it for me.
I want it too, but…
You're concerned about your mom.
Because you know she'll be devastated.
Well, knowing Emilia.
And I'm sure you know
your mom very well, Arnaldo.
She'll despise you for this.
Is that what you want?
It seems tonight, I don't have a choice.
If I decline their endorsement,
the party will persecute me.
I understand.
But you know, Arnaldo, you can
always choose another party.
But you can never choose…
your family.
[tense music mellows]
Senator Pablo Alcantara.
Good evening.
Tonight, we'll mark
another milestone for our party.
It's a shame Julio's not here
to witness this.
But I'm sure he will really be proud…
to see an Ardiente
in our senatorial lineup.
His heir, who will follow
in his footsteps.
I'm proud to present to you
the person who will complete
the senatorial lineup
of the Lakas Mamamayan Party.
A prolific leader.
A young leader whose heart
is for the people.
None other than…
Mayor Arnaldo Ardiente-Torillo.
[applause]
[tense music playing]
[tense music swells]
[Arnaldo sighs]
Emilia…
Thank you very much.
It's a great honor
to be given this responsibility.
Honestly, I'm very excited
for the opportunity that you gave me.
But I can't accept this.
Governor Emilia will be taking
my grandfather's place.
I'm sorry, but that is
the final decision of the party!
Take it or leave
the Lakas Mamamayan Party.
Well, Senator, if that's the case,
then we will leave the political party.
[dramatic music playing]
Thank you so much, Senator,
for the memories,
but no hard feelings.
Shall we go, Arnaldo?
Two birds, one stone.
Who's the better hunter now, Mr. Mayor?
[tense music swells]
Governor, what can you say about this?
-Governor, what happened?
-No comment.
Shouldn't they have chosen you, Governor?
You've got your scoop already.
Governor, please tell us
why that happened.
Senator, what's your comment on this?
-Come on. Here!
-Daddy?
-Come here, Natalie.
-Daddy.
-Let's go home.
-No, Daddy. What's happening?
What is happening is that
you will break up with Arnaldo!
No! That's not gonna happen,
Daddy. Are you crazy?
We have no use for that family anymore.
They are going down, Natalie.
And I won't let them drag us under!
-I love Arnaldo, Daddy.
-Wake up, Natalie!
He's just using you.
He will never love you.
-No.
-Because he wants someone else.
No, Daddy! [sobbing]
This is Ivy's fault.
This is Ivy's fault, Daddy.
She ruined everything.
-[groans]
-Natalie!
[growls]
You ruined everything!
You seduced Arnaldo to ruin our family.
[cries hysterically]
[glass shatters]
I will kill you!
[grunting]
A woman like you can't hurt me.
I warned you. Don't try me!
Move aside.
[Natalie sobbing]
I'm sorry, everyone. I have to go.
Excuse me.
[Ivy] Excuse me.
Emilia, Raul's gone.
He left.
Auntie, as of now,
I couldn't care less about him.
[tense music plays]
My only concern now is that traitor Pablo.
What's your plan?
[line ringing]
-Raul.
-Auntie, how's everything?
-Good thing you're here.
-Yes.
She's in the room.
Thanks.
IVY AGUAS FARMER'S HERO
[Tonio] I started working
as Emilia's hit man
when… when she was still mayor.
Your end is almost at hand, Emilia.
I'll make sure you pay for your crimes.
I swear it, Emilia.
We'll be leaving for Manila
first thing tomorrow, Natalie.
Say your goodbyes to Arnaldo.
We're never returning here again.
-What's going on?
-[car tires screeching]
[gunshots]
-[gunshot]
-[groans]
Good job.
I assume you heard about what
happened to Senator Alcantara,
and I can see you're already celebrating.
Don't you like that? That's one
less problem to deal with.
[phone ringing]
Jepoy?
Hello, Ivy. It's about Senator Alcantara.
Why? What happened?
He was ambushed, Ivy.
He's dead.
Jepoy, we need to move faster.
I won't let Emilia order her men to kill…
any more people than she already has.
Tonio is our key.
He will expose Emilia
for everything she's done.
And he will do that in court.
Make sure you do everything
I asked you to.
Don't worry, Ivy.
Just like what I promised Miss Prianka…
I'll do everything to help you succeed.
Thank you.
Wow, you seem to be in high spirits today.
Have your prayers been answered, Emilia?
[laughs]
Well, Auntie Clarita, you can say that
I'm slowly getting closer to what I want.
It's Claire. I want you
to call me Claire, Emilia.
Auntie Clarita, Claire.
It's just the same, Auntie.
Your niece is still going to be
a senator very soon.
And I won't get that
by just praying, Auntie.
So, what are you up to, my dear niece?
Well, Auntie, no one can stop me
from running for Senate.
Not even that stupid political party.
I know all my strengths and weaknesses.
That's why I need Ivy Aguas.
I need her influence, her power,
and most importantly, her money.
And thanks to Arnaldo,
I can play that woman like a puppet.
[tense music playing]
I will never lose you again,
no matter what.
Because you're mine.
-[panting]
-Mom? What happened to you?
-[shushes]
-[Tonio] Hey!
Lily… Run!
Where's my mom?
You said you'd take me to her.
Mom, what did they do to you?
Mom!
Lily?
Lily, my dear? Please, help me.
-Mom, where are you? Mom?
-Lily, help me!
-Mom?
-Lily. Lily!
Mom?
Lily.
-Mom.
-Lily.
-Lily, help me.
Lily.
Mom.
Mom?
-Mom!
-Lily.
Mom.
Mom?
-Mom!
-Lily.
Lily, help me.
I will, Mom. Mom.
Mom!
[tense music playing]
[quietly] Mom.
[tense music swells]
Ivy, does Nanny Carlotta know about this?
She left early for the market today.
-Come on, Ivy.
-Jepoy, this feels different.
-Is it because of your dream?
-Yes.
I don't know.
All I know is I want to see Tonio myself.
Because I'm not
just searching for justice,
but for the truth as well.
That's why I need to see Tonio.
Are you ready?
I just want to make sure, Ivy.
Are you ready to face the person
who killed your mother?
That's what I want to know, Jepoy.
I want to make sure
if my mom really is dead.
And if she is dead,
I want to know how he killed her.
I want answers to everything.
Because I want the Ardientes
to pay exactly what they owe me.
Including Diego?
I'm coming with you.
[car engine revs]
[suspenseful music playing]
[music fades]
Jepoy, thank you.
I know I make…
a lot of risky decisions.
Decisions that…
make you worry.
But you're still here.
Ever since you rescued me
from that perverted driver…
you've always been there for me.
You never left me. Thank you so much.
You saved me too, Ivy.
From my life in the streets.
Both you and Miss Prianka.
I owe you both my life.
That makes us even then.
I helped you because
you're a good friend, Jepoy.
To be honest, you do so much for me.
Sometimes, you risk your life
posing as one of Arnaldo's men.
But you're always there when I need you.
You do all those things for me…
to help me seek justice for my parents.
So, Jepoy…
thank you.
[soft music playing]
[suspenseful music swells]
Tonio's inside.
[action music playing]
Open it.
[doors squeak open]
[action music continues playing]
[action music swells]
[dramatic music playing]
How did you kill Camia Cruz?!
She was still alive
when I buried her in the forest.
Please forgive me.
That word means nothing to me now.
Everything you've worked
so hard for is crumbling down.
I don't know what to do. I need you.
[machine beeping]
[Diego] Why is she always with Mom?
What does she need from my family?
Why is she in Poblacion Ardiente?
[Loring] Let's say that she is Lily.
Then why does she need to pretend?
That's what I have to find out.
[man] Let's just wait for the
results of the DNA test.
I need the results in 24 hours.
I'm going to find you, Mom…
[theme music playing]